<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git on Code Chronicles (mostly)</title>
    <link>https://codicles.org/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git on Code Chronicles (mostly)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>sillyfellow@whybenormal.org (Dr. Sandeep Sadanandan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sillyfellow@whybenormal.org (Dr. Sandeep Sadanandan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codicles.org/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git pain optimisation</title>
      <link>https://codicles.org/post/git-pain-optimisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>sillyfellow@whybenormal.org (Dr. Sandeep Sadanandan)</author>
      <guid>https://codicles.org/post/git-pain-optimisation/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking a bit about git and the tools that help us with
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is a super powerful tool, but with quite complicated ways of
working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to most of the developers, the interface in the command line is
hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That usually leads them to using some UI which claims to make things
easier by abstracting details away (that is, the UI claims to do
the magic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All what I have seen so far tells me that this results in quite
unexpected behaviour (well, funnily enough sometimes we don&amp;rsquo;t even
know what is the expected behaviour). And every time this unexpected
things come along, one has to spend a good amount of time to fix it
(and that is possible only with the CLI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make it worse for me, in most of the projects I&amp;rsquo;m in, the person
who bears this pain is yours truly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mainly because the developers of the UI tool are probably
confused too, and finds it hard to communicate with the users
correctly - resulting in a tool which claims to do magic, but performs
the wrong trick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one and only solution I have seen which works (not claiming it is
easy), and completely avoids all or any kind of surprise is the git
command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use perhaps 2% of the power of git, but only from CLI and
very very rarely do I end up in a soup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My regular pain is probably ever so little more than the pain of the
UI tool user. But that is my worst pain, but never do I have to suffer
anything worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, please go ahead and learn those 10 git cli commands and get out of
the habit of using a fancy tool which merges in the wrong direction or
rebases incorrectly to drive you mad. That&amp;rsquo;ll pay off and keep your
pain minimal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
